좋아
어디까지 얘기했지?  그날은 2007년 6월이었어
인생은 기대하지 않았던 변환점을 맞았지  아빠 그냥 바로 엄마를 만난 부분으로 넘어가면 안돼요?
얘기를 1년은 하신것 같아요  얘야, 내가 하는 모든 얘기는 다 중요하단다
모든 얘기가 이야기의 한 부분이야  - 아빠 화장실 가도 될까요? - 안돼
2006년의 여름은 멋진 동시에 끔찍했지  나에겐 좋게 시작되었어
사실은 첫날은 정말 놀라웠지  난 마침내 로빈과 함께 하게 되었어
내가 내 인생의 최고로 멋진 밤을 보내고 있을때  너희 삼촌 마샬은 최악의 밤을 겪었지
- 그거야? 우린 헤어지는거야? - 마샬, 미안해, 난...  난 샌프란시스코로 가서 이 미술 프로그램을 하고..
우리 사이가 아닌 나 자신이 누군지 알아야겠어  그렇게 할 유일한 방법은
서로 잠시 연락을 안하면 좋겠어  잠시만?
평생은 어때?  니가 저 문을 나서면, 우린 끝이야
넌 평생 내 목소리를 못듣게 될거야  - 전화해야 겠어 - 안돼!
릴리가 그러지 말라고 했는데 전화하면  약해 보일뿐 아니라 후회하게 될거야
있지, 전화하고 싶어지면  날 먼저 찾아와
내가 니 얼굴 한방 먹여줄 테니까  넌 좋은 친구야, 테드
안녕, 그럼 그 뉴스 들었어?  니말은 릴리랑 마샬이 헤어지고 나서 릴리는 떠났고
어젯밤에 어떤 조금이라도 중요한 일이 일어나지 않았다는거?  응, 잘 알거야
어머! 정말 유감스럽다, 무슨 일이야?  릴리는 떠났고, 돌아오긴 할건지도 모르겠어
일어나서야 니 메세지 봤어  친구, 유감스럽다
정말 힘들겠는걸  내가 니 기분이 좋아질 뿐 아니라
적극적으로 흥분할 만한 얘기 해줄까? / 물론  역사상 처음으로 우리 세명은 동시에 싱글이야
난 이 날을 꿈꿔왔어 친구들 우린 이제 전설적이 될거야  우리 함께 이 도시를 차지할거야
언제든 한 여자가 예전 남친에게 앙갚음하고 싶으면 우리가 곁에 있어줄거야  언제든 한 여자가 아빠 문제를 마시고 떠들기로 푼다면 우리가 곁에 있어줄거야
언제든, 처녀 파티때 리무진을 타고 가다가 천장 지붕으로 머리를 들고 '뉴욕 잘 지내요!' 할때  우리는 그 '잘 된 뉴욕'이 될거야
신사분들, 우리는 이제...  이 놈들, 너희 했구나
How I Met Your Mother 2x01   번역: 박은희 (네이트 24 자유제작)
그 해 여름에 알게 된 한가지는  사랑이 시작되고, 사랑이 끝날 때
초기의 30일은 둘이 놀랍게도 비슷하지  한가지는, 둘다 침대에서 대부분 시간을 보낸단 거고
친구들은 너희 얘기를 견딜 수 없어하지  그리고 넌 바지를 잘 안 입게 되지
안녕 마샬 / 안녕 테드  배고프냐?
그래 뭘 먹을순 있겠지 그럼 날 그냥 살려둘거야  적어도 그 시나리오에선 니가 버리는 걸 하든데
오늘은 일요일이야 팬케이크의 날이라구  릴리가 팬케이크를 만들어줬었는데
니 팬케이크가 너무 좋아 정말 부드럽고, 정말 따뜻하고  정말 완벽한 모양의..
우리 그 팬케이크 얘기하는 거 맞아?  넌 뭘 먹어야 해, 뭐 갖다줄까? / 맥주?
아니 그거 어제 저녁으로 먹었잖아 / 알았어  나한테 남은게 있을거야
내내 집에만 있으면서 얻어보려 노력하지도 않는다고?  아니다, 니가 약혼자가 있을때 하는 짓이 그거지
여기 내려와서 축하해야지  마샬한텐 그 빨강머리 종양이 제거된거야
너 어린이용 책을 써야겠다  마샬이 뭘 해야될줄 알아?
마샬은 슬퍼하는 걸 멈춰야 해  내가 슬퍼질때 난 슬픈걸 멈추고 더 끝내주게 변했지
사실이야  겨우 한달밖에 안됐어
예전의 마샬로 돌아올 필요가 있어  - 어쨌든, 릴리가 이 난잡의 원인인걸 - 왜 이래 릴리도 좀 이해해줘봐
릴리도 우리 친구잖아 릴리는 자신이 누구인질 찾는중이야  자기가 누구인지?
나한테 전화하라 그래 내가 적어놨으니까  릴리는 이기적인데다가, 미숙하고
그리고... / 왜?  이런, 니 눈 정말 파랗다 / 테디 베어..
너무 유감스러워 하기도 힘들었지  나는 내 꿈의 여자와 사귀고 있었고, 잘 되갔으니깐
대부분은 그랬지  릴리 샴푸를 발견했어 그래 놓고갔어
릴리 냄새가 난다.. 라벤더 향과 조개껍질과 희망...  어쩐지 이국적이고 편안한 냄새가 동시에 느껴져
그거 내 샴푸야 / 미안  마샬이 안 잘줄 알았어 / 이런
벌써?  전화한다
마샬이 전화해! / 안들리는데  안 돼!
알았어! 안할게, 전화 안할거야  글쎄 내가 전화를 했는데 이걸 받았어
전화번호를 바꿨데  뭐 내가 스토커라도 되고 릴리는 너무 특별하셔?
거기 있는 유일한 한명인줄 아는데 샌프란시스코에만 릴리가 4명이 있어  그리고 같이 변태적 얘기를 나눠보니 다들 더 낫아보이던데?
내가 여기 있는거 알아? / 그래 안녕 로빈  이젠 그만 둬야 해
테드, 우린 데이트를 막 시작했어  우리 너무 성급히 굴지 말자고 동의했는데
웬일인지 우리한테는 애가 있는거야  밥도 혼자 못먹고, 많이 울고 밤새 깨어있고..
모유 수유는 시도해봤냐? 성공했어!  걔네는 9년동안 함께했어 아직 1개월 반밖에 안됐는걸
원래 페이스로 돌아올 시간이 필요해  어제 우리 바닥에서 잤다니깐
'무서운 영화'를 봤다구  이젠 엄한 태도를 취해야겠어
아파트에서 나오게 할 필요가 있어  마샬한텐 신선한 공기가 필요해
햇빛도 필요하구  음.. 햇빛(sunshine)이라..
신사 여러분.. '선샤인'양을 무대로 환영해 주십시오!  바니, 진짜 이게 도움이 될 것 같진 않다
왜 아직도 릴리를 극복 못한줄 알아?  바로 니가 아직도 릴리의 벗은 몸을 상상할수 있어서야
넌 그녀 가슴을 그만 생각하기 전까진 여자를 잊을 수 없다구  과학적 사실이야
평균의 남자의 뇌는 꽤 괜찮은 가슴 사진을 한정되게 저장해놓는다는 거야  니 하드엔 지금 릴리 껄로 꽉 차있는거 알아
정말 많이 들어있어  다른 여자 가슴 이미지로 덮어쓰기 전에는 극복하지 못해
이번 여행은 몇백만개의 가슴을 거치게 되겠지만  우린 여기서 시작할거야 친구, 한번에 둘 씩..
저건 넷으로 세야겠구나  재미있지, 밖에 나오니 날씨 좋지? 인디언스 팀은 구려요!
정말 나오니까 날씨 좋다   * 양키 팀 팬분들 야구장 스크린을 보시면서 *
* 깜짝 프로포즈를 하는 커플을 축하해주세요 *  모두 다 거짓말이야!
곧 니 마음을 아프게 할거라구!  우린 다 해봤어
야구장, 스트리퍼 팬케이크도 안먹겠데잖아  회복의 가망이 없는 것 같아
봤지? 이게 남자들의 문제점이야  실연의 비탄을 어떻게 대처할줄 모르지
그럼 처방전이 뭡니까? 에스트로겐 박사님?  하겐다즈 먹으면서 그날 끝날때까지 '러브 액츄얼리'보기?
그래, 그거였어  와, 언제부터 한거야?
어릴때 아빠가 가르쳐줬어  내가 외롭거나 우울할때 여기 오면
총도.. 재미있단걸 상기하지  있지? 테드는 총을 반대하는 타입이야
그래서 테드는 절대 알면 안돼  내가 총 들고 있는 거 무섭구나?
아니 내 말은.. 테드한테 말하지 마  너도 해볼래?
당근이지  오 예
이게 필요했어  정말 무기력했는데
이건.. 정말 힘이 생겨!  총포의 반동이 일어나단건 알려줬어야 했는데
알려줘야 겠어, 마샬은 집에 와서 미소를 짓더라  같이 잤어?
사실 그걸 제안했던게 3일 전이었거든  가끔 넌 여성적인 면을 건드려주기만 하면 돼
하하, 호호, 예예!  그럼, 축하해 넌 마샬의 여름을 기분좋게 만들어준 첫번째 사람이야
니가 이겼어  뭘 이겼는데? / 뭔지 알아? 이번 주말에 어디 데려갈거야
정말? 좋은데?  이모랑 삼촌의 몬타그 해변가에 별장을 가지고계신데 정말 로맨틱해
우리 삼촌은 거기서 세번이나 불륜을 저지르셨데  와, 정말 좋은 장소인가 봐? 너희 삼촌 사진을 봤거든
정말 로맨틱하겠는데 마침내 우리 둘만의 시간을 보내고..  마샬도 괜찮을것 같아?
당근이지, 친구  난 훨씬 좋아졌어
- 그냥, 내 차도 갖구 가 - 정말? 고마워  그리고 뭐 필요하면 낮이든 밤이든 전화만 줘
있지? 절대 나한테 전화하지 마  왜? 뭐가 문제야? / 이거 릴리 신용카드 청구서야
주소를 바꾸는 걸 깜박했나봐 / 그래서?  샌프란시스코 어디서 무슨 돈을 썼을까?
안돼, 이걸 보면 기분만 안좋아져  너 이미 향상되고 있다구, 안돼
이건 나한테 고마워 해  넌 좋은 친구야 테드
8월 5일 한 번, 티켓 무슨 티켓?  조지 클린튼과 피 펑크 얼스타스 (* George Clinton & P.Funk Stars)
8월 10일 한 번 테니스 백화점에서  8월 18일 두 번, 마리오 술집 에다가 이거 봐, 펫 팔라스
무슨 뜻인지 몰라?  와 마리오 술집이라니 바람피고 다니기 완벽한 장소군요
제 귀여운 릴리 씨를 위하면 뭐든지 다 하지요  펑크의 전설 조지 클린튼씨 절 콘서트에서 발견하시곤
무대로 올리셔서 커트니콕스 스타일로 같이 춤추게 해주신거 고마워요  같이 테니스 쳐준거 고맙소
마샬은 9년간 같이 테니스 치자고 했었는데  전 안쳤어요, 왜냐면 전 마샬을 정말로 사랑하지 않았거든요
선물도 가져왔소  흰족제비요? 좀 있다 '펫 팔라스'에서 모이를 사줘야 겠네요
전 항상 하나를 기르고 싶었어요  마샬은 남 몰래 족제비혐오증이 있었거든요
그건 아무한테 말하지 말라고 했던 비밀이었나 본데요  네 맞아요
사랑해요 펑크의 전설 조지 클린튼씨  나도 사랑하오, 릴리
맞소 마샬 릴리는 내꺼요  이제 내 머리를 갖고 놀게도 해줄거요
여태껏 들어본 얘기중에 정말 미친 소리다  그래 왜 족제비를 싫어해? 귀엽잖아
왜냐면 로빈, 걔네는 복슬하게 부풀은 쥐 같잖아  이 청구서는 한 달 전 쯤에 쓴거잖아 / 내 말이
최근 청구 내역은 온라인 계좌를 확인해봐야 할걸  너 2시간 전 쯤.. 신용카드 내역도 볼수 있을걸?
근데 있지.. 그러진 마  왜 얘기 했어! 왜 얘기 했냐고!
비밀번호가 필요해, 마샬은 모를껄  비밀번호를 알았군
오늘 아침에 5가에 있는 켈렛 호텔에서 썼어  못믿겠어, 릴리가 뉴욕에 돌아와있는거야
믿을 수 없군, 릴리가 뉴욕에 다시 와있어?  난 릴리가 돌아오면 전화 줄거라 생각했어
그게 여지껏 여름 내내 내가 정신을 차린 이유였는데  이게 '정신 차리기'였어?
있지? 전화할래 / 안돼  넌 전화 못해 그런다구 바뀌지 않아
너 일루 와  있지, 우리가 주말에 놀아가면
너 마샬 내내 감시하면서 호텔에 전화 안하나 확인할래?  뭐 애를 돌보라고?
한시간당 20달러  그리고 피자 먹을 돈도 추가
그래 공짜로 해주지 않으면  매번 우리랑 같이 놀때 이걸 보는건 어때?
- 이리와, 내 귀여운 파란 눈 - 오 우 슈가슈가  알았어, 할게, 커플짓 그만해
마샬!  테드, 어쩔수 없었어! 우린 9년간 함께했는데 여태껏 했던 모든게 헛수고..
안녕하세요 릴리 씨 방 연결해주세요  고맙습니다
테드 못 끊어 / 끊어! 지금 끊어! 끊으라구!  네?
남자가 받았어  방에 남자가 있어
거기 가봐야 겠어  거기 내려가서 내가 사랑한다고 말하고
날 다시 받아달라고 빌어야 겠어  안돼면 무릎도 꿇어볼꺼야
마샬 그럴 순 없어 / 정말? 왜 안돼는데?  57일째, 내가 똑바로 말하게 되는데 걸린 시간이지
왜냐면 넌 불쌍해 보이니깐!  미안해, 하지만 넌 지금 마샬이 아니야
너는 불쌍하게, 흐느끼는 샴푸 냄새를 맡는 마샬의 유령이야  솔직히, 너같은 남자는 릴리같은 여자때문에 별걸 시도하지 않아
확실히 시도해 봐야 하는게 누구 인 줄이나 알아?  마샬, 진짜 마샬이야
니가 지금 거기로 내려간다면  넌 진짜 마샬한텐 큰 실수만 안겨 줄거고 용서도 안해줄거야
어쨌든 내가 뭘 말하든지 넌 반대로 하겠지  그럼.. 좋은 주말 보내
니 인생 잘 망쳐봐  이리와 로빈
우리 아직도 차 빌릴수 있는거지?  뻔뻔하군, 차 빌리는것 땜에 뻔뻔해져
왜? / 난 아무 말 안했어  - 내가 너무했다 생각하지? - 난 아무말 안했다구
날 너무하다고 비난할 줄 몰랐어  니가 먼저 엄한 태도를 취하자며
그래 엄한 태도를 말했지 올가미를 씌우란건 아니었어  9미리(권총)를 건네주는건 괜찮다?
그래.. 말해줬어  - 그럼 너 총신도구나? - 아니 난 총 애호가야
- 너 매년 얼마나 많은 사람이 매년 죽음을 - 헌법 수정 제2조에선 무장 권리를..  좋아 좋아 알았어
내가 너무했어  바니한테 어떻게 됐나 전화해보자
바니입니다  어디있어?
모금 행사중이야  어린 여학생들이 전문대 갈 학자금을 모으는 걸 돕고있지
스크립 클럽이구나? 멋진데 마샬 괜찮아?  응 여기 있어 좋아
마샬 테드한테..  벌써에요?
마샬은 갔어 / 놓쳤어?  이럴수가, 마샬은 호텔로 쫓아갈거야
이런, 좋아, 계획이 있어 넌 호텔에 가서 마샬을 찾고  난 여기서 랩댄스를 받고 있지 3시부터..
- 너희 삼촌 별장에 온수욕조 있어? - 정말 좋은 거 하나 있지  릴리 씨 방이 어딘줄 아세요?
마샬 / 안녕  어떻게 됐어?
난 릴리 층에 올라갔는데  머릿속에 말할 내용을 생각하고 있었어
여름내내 릴리한테 얘기하고 싶었던 것들  사랑과, 충직과, 존중...
내가 문을 두드렸을때  그럼 릴리 새 남친을 때려눕혔다고?
응, 릴리 남친이 아니었어  그럼 누군데?
조이 애달리언이었어  비록 그는 신분 위장 절도를 위해 몇년간 여러 가명을 쓰고 다녔지
사실은, 여름 초에..  정말 부끄럽네요
제가 잔돈을 가져왔을것 같은데..  알아요, 죄송해요
오 여깄네요, 아 이건 단추였네요  단추였어요
신용카드도 받나요? / 물론이죠  그럼 릴리는 우리 동네에 온게 아니네
남자친구도 없고 그럼 좋은거지? / 그래  그 신용카드 내역이 나한텐 유일하게 남은 연락처였어
어디있는지, 뭘 하는 지 몰라  릴리는 내 삶의 전부였다구 친구 근데 떠났으니..
대학교 첫날  난 나타나서 정말 긴장해서
내 방에 올라 갔는데 거기 내 룸메이트가 있었어  침대에 누워서 발은 벽에 올리고 헤드폰을 끼고
아무것도 신경 안쓴다는 미소를 지었지..  행복해 보였고, 자신감 있고, 뭐든 두려워 보이지 않았어
그 남자애는 바로 너였어  릴리를 만나기 바로 전의 너
있지 / 응?  나 그날 취했어
정말이야 너무 취해서 니가 학장인줄 알았어  내말은 릴리 없는 너만의 버전이 있어
그건 이런 모습이 아냐  그 남자가 릴리 신분을 훔친것처럼 니가 릴리한테 신분을 빼앗기면 안돼
알았어  좋아
해결했어  내일부터, 난 괜찮아 질거야
건배 / 건배  하지만 괜찮아지지 않았지
인생은 그렇게 쉽게 풀리지 않거든  다음날 양말같은걸 찾아서는 우리는 처음으로 되돌아갔지
그러다가는 어느날 아침..  테드, 이거 봐야겠어
뭔데?  마샬?
너 뭐해?  일요일이잖아
팬케이크 먹는 날이잖아  67일 하고도 정말 구역질나게 맛없는 팬케이크가 들었어
마샬은 죽음에서 돌아왔지  왜냐면 야구장이나 스트리퍼나 총이 도울수 있을지 몰라도
실연의 애탄을 정말 치료해줄 수 있는 유일한 건.. 시간이야
TED: Okay where were we?
It was June of 2006,
and life had just taken an unexpected turn.
Dad, can't you just skip ahead
to the part where you meet Mom?
I feel like you've been talking for like a year.
Honey, all this stuff I'm telling you is important.
It's all part of the story.
Could I go to the bathroom?
No.
The summer of 2006 was both wonderful and awful.
For me, it started out great.
In fact, day one was amazing.
I'd finally gotten together   with Robin.
But while I'd been off having   one of the best nights
of my life, your uncle Marshall
had been having one   of the worst nights of his.
* Crying in the street... *
MARSHALL:  So that's it?
We're breaking up?
Marshall, I'm sorry. I just...
I just need to go
to San Francisco and do this art program and-and figure out
who I am outside of us.
And the only way
that I can do that is if... if we don't talk for a while.
For a while.
Try never, okay?
You walk out that door, and we're done.
You're never going to hear my voice again.
I should call her. No, No.
Ted it is-- If you call her
when she asked you not to you're just going to look weak
and you're going to regret it.
Now, listen, whenever you feel like calling her,
you come find me first.
And I will punch you in the face.
You're a good friend, Ted.
(knock at door)
Hey.
So, did you hear the big news?
You mean how Lily and Marshall broke up,
and Lily's gone and nothing else
even remotely important happened last night,
yeah, I think he knows.
Oh, my God.
I-I'm so sorry. Wh--
What happened?
Well, she left.
And I don't even know if she's coming back.
I didn't get your message until I woke up.
Bro, I am so sorry.
Thanks.
I know it must be tough,
but are you ready to hear something
that will not only make you feel better,
but will actively excite you?
Sure.
For the first time, ever,  the three of us are single
at the same time.
I've dreamed about this day, boys,
and it's going to be
legendary.
Together, we will own this city.
Anytime a girl wants to get back at her ex-boyfriends,
we'll be there.
Anytime a girl wants to solve her father issues
through promiscuity and binge drinking, we will be there.
Anytime a bachelorette party drives through the city
in a limo, sticking their heads out the sunroof shouting,
(mimicking female voice): "What's up, New York?"
we will be what is up New York.
Gentlemen, we are about to embark on...
Aw, man, you guys did it, didn't you?
One thing I learned that summer
is that when love   is beginning...
(moans)
...and love is ending,
the first 30 days   are remarkably similar.
For one thing, you spend   most of your time in bed.
(moans)
(groans)
Your friends can't stand   to listen to you.
He's so ticklish.
It was a really beautiful song.
So... stupid, man. (mimicking choking)
And you never seem   to wear pants.
(sighs)
Hey, Marshall.
Hey, Ted.
You hungry? What's the point?
I could eat some food.
It's just going to leave me.
Well, at least in that scenario you get to do the dumping.
Come on, it's Sunday.
It's pancakes day.
Lily always made the pancakes.
God, I loved her pancakes.
So soft.
So warm.
So perfectly shaped.
Are we still talking about her pancakes?
Come on, you got to eat something; what can I get you?
Beer.
No, that's what you had for dinner.
Fine.
Then I'll just have leftovers.
BARNEY:  So, he stays home
all the time not getting laid?
No, see,
that's what you do when you have a fianc\e.
He should be down here celebrating.
He's free.
He got that redheaded tumor removed.
You should write and illustrate children's books.
You know what Marshall needs to do.
He needs to stop being sad.
When I get sad, I stop being sad and be awesome instead.
True story.
It's only been a month.
He just needs to go at his own pace.
Anyway, Lily's the one who caused this whole mess.
Hey, cut her some slack.
She's our friend, too.
She's just trying to figure out who she is.
Figure out who she is?
Yeah, she should call me; I got a whole list.
She's selfish.
She's immature.
She's...
What?
God, your eyes are so blue.
Aw, Teddy Bear.
(mimics sword unsheathing) Oh that's a...
(groans)
(coughs)
Yeah, it was hard to feel   too bad.
I was dating the woman   of my dreams,
and things were going great.
Well, for the most part.
So, I found her shampoo.
MARSHALL: I guess she left it here.
It smells like her.
Like lavender and seashells and hope.
Somehow,
erotic and comforting all at the same time.
That's my shampoo.
Oh, sorry.
Mmm, I thought he'd never go to sleep.
(moans)
Uh-oh.
Already?
He's calling her.
I don't hear any-- He's calling her.
No. (screams)
MARSHALL: Okay, you're right, I won't call her.
I will not call her.
Well, I called her.
And get this,
she changed her number.
What, like I'm going to stalk her,
or something? Like she's so special.
Like she's the only Lily Aldrin out there.
'Cause there are four others in the San Francisco area alone,
and they all seem a lot better than her
based on the brief conversations I had with them.
Does he know I'm in here?
Yeah, hey, Robin.
Anyways, one of the Lily Aldrins said...
This has to stop.
Ted, we just started dating.
We agreed we don't want to move too fast,
and yet somehow, we have a baby.
He can't feed himself.
He cries a lot, he keeps us up all night.
Have you tried breast-feeding?
Nailed it!
Look, they were together nine years.
It's only been a month and a half.
He just needs to go at his own pace.
He slept on our floor last night, Ted.
He watched a scary movie.
It is time for some tough love.
We need to get him out of that apartment.
He needs fresh air.
He needs sunshine.
Mmm, sunshine.
ANNOUNCER (over speaker): Please welcome to the stage, Sunshine.
All right, I really don't think this is going to help.
Do you know why you're not over Lily yet?
It's 'cause you can still picture her naked.
You can't get over a woman until you can no longer
picture her boobs; it's a scientific fact.
The average male brain can only store a finite number
of boob images or "b-pegs".
And your hard drive's filled to capacity with Lily's.
There are a lot of them.
Well, they won't go away until you overwrite them
with images of other women's boobs.
Now, this journey may take
as many as a million boobs,
so we begin here tonight, my friend.
Two at a time.
Those count as four.
Yeah.
This is fun right?
We're outside, it's a beautiful day.
The Indians are winning.
I got to admit,
it is really nice to be outside.
ANNOUNCER (over speaker): Yankee fans,
please turn your attention to the Diamond Vision
for a special seventh-inning-stretch surprise.
Oh, no.
(crowd sighing)
(applause and cheering)
It's all a big lie!
She's just going to break your heart.
(crowd booing)
You can drag me out of here, but she has no soul!
We've tried everything-- baseball, strippers.
The guy still won't eat a damn pancake.
I think he's beyond repair.
See, this is the problem with guys.
You don't know how to deal with heartbreak.
Oh, and what's your prescription, Dr. Estrogen?
Eat Haagen-Dazs and watch Love Actually,
till your periods sync up.
(Ted, Barney laughing)
Yeah, that's the stuff.
Oh, my God.
How long have you been doing this?
Well, my dad taught me to me shoot when I was a kid.
Whenever I'm feeling lonely or depressed, I come here,
and it reminds me that...
guns are fun.
(chuckles lightly)
Um, you know, Ted is kind of against guns.
And that's why
Ted's never going to find out about this.
Whoa, that sounded kind of scary
with me holding a gun, didn't it?
No, I-I just mean,
please don't tell Ted.
You want to try?
Only hell yeah.
Oh, yeah, yeah, this is what I needed.
I felt so powerless this whole time,
but this... (laughs)
this is power.
This is... (gasps)
I should of mentioned the recoil.
I got to hand it to you, when he got home,
Marshall was smiling-- did you sleep with him?
'Cause I was actually, like, three days away
from suggesting that.
Sometimes, all you need is to get in touch
with your feminine side.
(laughing)
Yeah, yeah!
Well, congratulations.
You're the first person to cheer him up all summer.
You win. Oh, what do I win?
I'll tell you what you win:
I'm taking you away this weekend.
You are? Mmm.
That's so nice.
Yeah, my aunt and uncle have a beach house
out in Montauk, oh, it's really romantic.
My uncle's had like three affairs there.
Wow, must be a nice house,
I've seen pictures of your uncle.
This is going to be so great.
We'll finally get some time alone.
Are you sure Marshall's going to be okay with this?
Yeah, absolutely.
Dude, I'm doing much better. Oh.
In fact, take my car.
Really? Yeah.
Hey, thanks... and, hey,
if you need anything day or night, just call me--
You know what, please don't call me.
What? What's wrong?
It's, uh, Lily's credit card bill.
She must have forgotten
to switch her address.
So?
So, I wonder what kind of charges she's making
out there in San Francisco. No.
No, no good can come from looking at this.
You've made too much progress already.
I know but I just, maybe the-- No!
You're going to thank me for this.
You're a good friend, Ted.
August 5th, one charge-- tickets.
To what? George Clinton and the P-Funk All-Stars.
August 10th, one charge: Tennis Emporium.
August 18th, two charges:
Mario's Bistro and, get this, Pet Palace.
You guys see what this means, right?
Wow, Mario's Bistro.
What a perfect place to whore around.
Only the best for my little Lily pad.
Oh, funk legend George Clinton,
I am so glad you spotted me at your concert
and dragged me onstage to dance with you Courtney Cox-style.
And I'm so glad you agreed to play tennis with me.
Aw.
You know, Marshall tried to get me
to play tennis for nine years,
but I didn't do it, because I never truly loved him.
I got you a gift.
Oh.
A ferret.
Oh, I'll buy it some food next door at the Pet Palace.
Oh, I've always wanted one,
but Marshall had this secret phobia of ferrets.
I bet that's something he made you promise not to tell nobody.
(laughing): It was.
Oh.
I love you, funk legend George Clinton.
I love you, too, Lily.
That's right, Marshall, she's all mine.
Now I'm gonna let her play with my hair.
* Ow, we want the funk *
* Give up the funk... *
That's the craziest thing I've ever heard.
Yeah, why are you afraid of ferrets?
They're adorable.
Because, Robin, they're like fuzzy, tube-shaped rats.
Plus, those charges are from, like, a month ago.
Exactly. For new charges,
you have to go to her online account.
You can see credit card activity from, like, two hours ago.
But, you know, don't.
Why do you talk?
Why do you talk?!
BARNEY: He needs her password.
It's not like he has her password.
Ooh, this is good, he has her password.
There's a charge from earlier today:
the Kellett Hotel on 5th.
I don't believe this.
Lily's back in New York.
I can't believe this.
Lily's in New York?
I-I guess I've been thinking
when she got back, she'd call me.
That's really the only reason
I've been able to hold it together so far this summer.
This has been "holding it together"?
Okay, you know what? I'm calling her.
No. Ted, give me the phone.
You're not calling her, this changes nothing.
You, come here.
Look, while we're away this weekend, can you keep
an eye on him, make sure he doesn't call that hotel?
You want me to babysit him?
(laughs) 20 bucks.
An hour.
And money for pizza.
Uh, yeah, how about you do it for free
or every time we hang out, you have to watch this?
Come here. Ooh.
My little blue-eyed baby, baby lips. Ooh, ooh, sugar, sugar...
Okay, I'll do it!
Stop being a couple.
Marshall. Marshall, Marshall!
Ted, I know I shouldn't do this, but I have to! You call her
We were together for nine years! and everything we've been working so hard for
is completely flushed down the toi...
Hello, Lily Aldrin's room, please.
Thank you. Hang up now.
Ted, I can't hang up now. Hang up now.
The missiles are in the air, and I know that you don't approve.
Hang up. Hello.
Uh, a guy answered.
There's-there's a guy in her room.
I'm going down there.
BARNEY: Dude, you can't do that.
I have to go down there, and I have
to tell her I love her; I have to beg her to take me back,
even if I have to get down on my knees.
Marshall, you can't do that. Oh, really, why not?
TED:  56 days.
That's how long it took me   to get right about here.
Because you're pathetic!
I'm sorry, but right now, you are not Marshall.
You are the miserable,
whining, shampoo-sniffing ghost of Marshall,
and frankly, a guy like you
doesn't have a shot in hell with a girl like Lily.
You know who might have a shot
somewhere down the line?
Marshall.
The real Marshall.
But if you go down there right now like this, you're going
to blow it for him, and he's never going to forgive you.
Of course, whatever I say,
you're just going to do the opposite,
so have a great weekend.
Good luck screwing up your life.
Come on, Robin.
(clears throat)
Is it still okay if we borrow the car?
Bold. Bold to go for the car.
What?
I didn't say a thing.
You think I was too hard on him.
I didn't say a thing. (scoffs)
I can't believe you're accusing me of being too hard on him.
You're the one who said "tough love."
Yeah, tough love, not "hand the guy a noose."
Oh, but it's okay to hand him a nine millimeter?
Yeah, he told me.
So you're a gun nut?
No, I'm a gun enthusiast. Do you know how many people
are killed each year The Second Amendment
protects my right to bear arms... in accidents...
All right, all right, all right.
I was too hard on him.
A little.
(laughs softly)
I'm going to call Barney, see how they're doing.
(phone rings) Go for Barney.
Oh, hey, where are you guys?
We're at a fundraiser,
helping young women raise money for community college.
Strip club, nice.
Is Marshall okay? (laughs)
Yeah, he's here and he's great.
Uh, hang on. Marshall?
Tell Ted that--
Uh-oh.
Already?
What? What uh-oh?
He's gone.
You lost him?
I can't believe this.
He's going to go down to that hotel.
Crap, you're right.
Okay, okay, here's the plan, here's the plan.
You go down to the hotel and find him.
I'll stay here and get a lap dance.
On three. One, two...
Barney!
Was there a hot tub at your uncle's place?
A really nice one.
Hi, uh, could you tell me what room Lily Aldrin's in?
Marshall.
(chuckling): Hey.
What happened?
Well, I went up to Lily's floor,
and I had this little speech   in my head--
everything I've been wanting   to say to her all summer
about love, loyalty, respect.
I knocked on the door.
So you knocked out Lily's new boyfriend?
Yeah.
It wasn't Lily's boyfriend.
What? Who-- who was it?
TED:  His name was Joey Adalian,   although he went by a number
of aliases in his years   as an identity thief.
Apparently,   earlier in the summer...
LILY: Oh, this is so embarrassing.
I-I could have sworn I had some change.
I know, I know.
I'm sorry.
Oh, here we go.
No, that's-that's a button.
It was a button.
Do you, uh, take credit cards?
Yes, I do.
So Lily's not back in town,
and she doesn't have a boyfriend?
Th-That's good news, right?
Yeah.
I don't know.
Those credit card charges
were the only remaining connection I had to her.
I don't know where she is or what she's doing.
She was my whole life, man, and now she's-she's gone.
You know, first day of college, I showed up,
I was so freaked out,
and-and I got up to my room, and there was my roommate,
lying on the bed with his feet up on the wall.
Had headphones on, big smile on his face
like he just didn't give a crap.
Happy.
Confident. Not afraid of anything.
That guy was you.
You before you met Lily.
Ted?
Yeah?
I was high that day.
I was.
I was so high, I thought you were the dean.
Wh-What I'm saying is
there's a version of you without Lily,
and it's not this.
You can't let Lily steal your identity
the way that guy stole hers.
Okay.
Okay, resolved.
Starting tomorrow, I'm going to start being okay.
(chuckles)
Cheers. Cheers.
* *
But he wasn't,
'cause that's not   how life works.
The next day, he found one   of her socks or something,
and we were back to square one.
And then, one morning...
Ted, I think you should see this.
Oh, no, what now?
Marshall, what are you doing?
It's Sunday.
It's pancakes day.
It took him 67 days
and one really disgusting   batch of pancakes...
So good.
Mmm. So good.
...but Marshall had come back   from the dead.
Because while baseball,   strippers, and guns can help,
the only thing that can really   heal a broken heart is time.
* I try to laugh about it *
* Cover it all up with lies *
* Hiding the tears from my eyes *
* 'Cause boys don't cry. *